CHETHAN MYSURU RADHAKRISHNA

Pursuing Master's in Data and Knowledge Engineering

@ chethanmr.2694@gmail.com

J +49 17636817295

Arnold-Zweig Strasse 4, 39120, Magdeburg, Germany

Magdeburg, Germany

thethanmysore.github.io/portfolio

in chethan-radhakrishna-94310010b/

chethanMysore



ABOUT ME!

I am a data science enthusiast with an inclination towards visual exploration of trends in data. I am also a skilled web developer with a collective experience of 4 years. However, I believe in the idea that "What we know is a drop and what we don't know is an ocean".

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer - Work Student

Metratec Gmbh

June 2019 - Ongoing

Magdeburg

Working as a full stack web developer. Handled API integration with react-redux dashboards. worked on real time data using web sockets. worked on event sourcing and reSolve(a CQRS framework built using node.js). Managed Gitlab pipeline and docker configurations with yaml.

Technologies: Reactjs, nodejs, reSolve, web sockets, node-red

Software Engineer

Happiest Minds Technologies Pvt Ltd

October 2016 - January 2019

India

Contributed as a full stack web developer. Worked on ASP.NET MVC applications and Web API services built on .NET framework 4.6.2 and .NET core. Worked on react.js and redux to implement stateful frontend designs. Worked exclusively on Health Care domain with the knowledge of online data exchange standards such as HL7. Worked on AWS EC2, S3 buckets, Simple Mail Service and Lambda(for deploying micro services). As a billable resource, interacted with clients to understand requirements and effectively communicated the innovative ideas to solve their problems.

Technologies: ASP.NET MVC/WebAPI, C, Reactjs, nodejs, AWS

PROJECTS

Interpretable Machine Learning to Understand Participant Evolution in Longitudinal Cohort Study Data

Otto-von-Guericke University

October 2019 - March 2020

The project aims at identifying evolutionary trends in longitudinal cohort data of a German population in Pomerania. The study focuses on explainable AI to explore the results of a machine learning model to derive critical factors influencing the diagnosis of Hepatic Steatosis. Worked on pre-processing, R-API development and visualization of model results using react-redux dashboard.

Technologies Used: R, react.js, redux, saga, canvas.js(for interactive graph visualizations)

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Data and Knowledge Engineering

Otto-von-Guericke University, Magdeburg

2019 - 2022 (Ongoing)

Coursework:

- Visual Analytics
- Machine Learning
- Data Mining
- Information Retrieval
- Deep Learning
- Distributed Data Management
- Data Management for Engineering Applications

B.E. in Computer Science and Engineering

Vidyavardhaka College of Engineering, India

= 2012 - 2016

SKILLS

Programming:

R
Python
SQL
mongoDB
Node.js
React.js
C#
C++
Java

Libraries: Scikit-Learn

Keras

Tensorflow NLTK

spaCy

gensim

Information Retrieval System

Otto-von-Guericke University

October 2019 - January 2020

This is a console java application which indexes files and directories and allows users to execute boolean queries on them. Here we used Apache Lucene to tokenize, index and query text in a directory(nested) or files. The application aims at achieving disambiguation of search terms and ranking of results based on relevance score. **Technologies Used: Apache Lucene, java, maven**

Gesture Recognition For Interactive Systems Using Kinect V2

Vidhyavardhaka College of Engineering

November 2015 - April 2016

Developed a WPF application to recognize user gestures using Microsoft Kinect V2 sensor. The application binds different mouse and keyboard inputs to gestures performed by users and thereby allowing them to interact with the system. Authentication of users is performed with face recognition algorithm developed using PCA(Principal Component Analysis) to compare grey scale images of faces. Technologies Used: .NET framework 4.5, WPF, Kinect V2 SDK, C#

| IDEs: | Visual Studio | Eclipse | Jupyter |
|----------|------------------|-----------|---------|
| Goog | le Colab | | |
| Versio | n Control and Cl | CD: Git I | _ab TFS |
| Octo | ous Jenkins | Docker | |
| | | | |
| LAN | IGUAGES | 5 | |
| English | | | |
| Eligiisi | 1 | | |
| Kanna | | • • | • • • |
| | | • • | • • • |

German

PUBLICATIONS

Journal Article

• Chethan M R Adarsh M V Akarsh M S Karunesh Gurkar, Prashanth Kumar (Guide) (2016). "Gesture Recognition for Interactive Systems Using Kinect v2". In: *International Journal of Innovative Research in Computer and Communication Engineering (IJIRCCE)*, 4(5):9186–9191, 05 2016. ISSN: 2320-9801. DOI: 10.15680/IJIRCCE.2015.0405108. URL: http://www.ijircce.com/upload/2016/may/108_22_Gesture_2%20HARD.pdf.

ACHIEVEMENTS

'Individual Excellence Award' for outstanding contribution to the project and customer happiness.



'Mindful Egg Head Award' for demonstrating good composure and interpersonal skills.



Won 3rd place in the technical project exhibition, 'Vivacious-E16' held at Vidhyavardhaka College of Engineering